复仇就要冷血
“克林昂古谚”
你以为我在玩性虐待吗？
Do you find me sadistic?
我敢说现在我能在你头上煎个蛋...
You know l'll bet I could fry an egg on your head right now...
如果我想的话
...if I wanted to.
知道吗 小乖乖...
You know, kiddo.
我相信
...l'd like to believe...
即使现在你还很清醒...
...you're aware enough, even now...
知道我不是在玩性虐待
...to know that there is nothing sadistic in my actions.
或许我会和那些无聊人玩
Maybe towards those other jokers...
但不和你玩
...but not you.
知道吗 小乖乖 现在...
No, kiddo at this moment...
是我...
...this is me...
...最痛苦的时候
...at my most masochistic.
比尔
Bill...
这是你的骨肉
it's your baby...
昆丁塔伦提诺第四部作品
乌玛・舒曼
片名: 追杀比尔 第一卷
# 当我五岁 他六岁 #
# 两小无猜 骑木马 #
# 他穿黑衣 我穿白 #
# 骑马打仗 总他赢 #
# 碰 碰 他开枪打我 #
# 碰 碰 我应声落马 #
# 碰 碰 可怕的枪声 #
# 碰 碰 爱人打中我 #
# 岁月如梭 季节换 #
# 我长大后 就要他 #
# 爱人总是 笑着说 #
# 记得儿时 一起玩 #
# 碰 碰 我开枪打你 #
# 碰 碰 你应声落马 #
# 碰 碰 可怕的枪声 #
# 碰 碰 我曾打中你 #
# 音乐响起 人们唱 #
# 教堂钟声 为我响 #
# 不知为何 他离去 #
# 至今依然 为他泣 #
# 不曾对我 说再见 #
# 甚至不愿 撒个谎 #
# 碰 碰 他开枪打我 #
# 碰 碰 我应声落马 #
# 碰 碰 可怕的枪声 #
# 碰 碰 爱人打中我 #
[第一章 － 2]
[加州 巴沙迪那市]
(玫瑰花车之都)
来了
Coming!
莎 怎么这么早！
Sarah, cannot believe you are early.
你想干嘛 嗯？！有啥本事？！
What you going to do now, huh?! What you got?!
饶不了你 准备好了吧！ 来呀！
Got your ass. Wrap it up! Come on!
好啊 来呀 婊子
Okay. Come on, bitch.
来呀
Come on.
放马过来
Bring it on.
- 妈咪 我回来了  - 嗨 宝贝
- Mommy, I'm home.
- Hey, baby.
学校一切都好吗？
How was school?
妈咪 你怎么啦 客厅怎么啦？
Mommy, what happened to you and the TV room?
你那只专门捣蛋的狗跑进客厅来造反了
Your good-for-nothing dog got into the living room and acted a damn fool.
就变成这样啦 宝贝
That's what happened baby.
是巴尼干的？
Barney did this?
宝贝 你不能过来这边
Baby. Now, you can't come in here.
到处都是碎玻璃 不小心会割到你的
There's broken glass everywhere and you could cut yourself.
这是妈咪好久没见的老朋友
This is an old friend of Mommy's I ain't seen in a long time.
嗨 甜心
Hi, honey.
我叫(消音) 你叫什么？
I'm (BLEEP) What's your name?
她叫妮琪
Her name is Nikki.
妮琪...
Nikki.
美丽的小姑娘 美丽的名字
Such a pretty name for such a pretty girl.
你几岁啦 妮琪？
How old are you, Nikki?
妮琪...(消音)在问你话呢
Nikki. (BLEEP) asked you a question.
我四岁
I'm 4.
四岁啦...
4 years old, eh?
你知道 我以前也有个女儿...
You know, I had a ittle girl once.
现在也该四岁了
She'd be about 4 now.
宝贝 妈咪的朋友和我有些大人的事要谈
Now baby, me and Mommy's friend got some grown-up talk to talk about.
我要你现在进房间去 直到我叫你出来为止
So go in your room now and leave us alone til I tell you to come out.
好吗？
Okay?
妮琪！
Nikkia!
现在立刻进房间去
In your room. Now.
来点咖啡吗？
You want some coffee?
嗯 好啊
Yeah. Sure
这家女主人的名字是吉妮・贝尔
This Pasadena homemaker's name is Jeanne Bell.
她先生是劳伦斯・贝尔
Her husband is Dr. Lawrence Bell.
不过四年前我们认识的时候 她的名字叫芙妮塔・格林
But back when we were acquainted four years ago, her name was Vernita Green.
她的代号是“铜头”(一种蛇的名称) 我的代号是“黑曼巴”(一种极毒的蛇)
Her code name was Copperhead. Mine, Black Mamba.
有纸巾吗？
Do you have a towel?
有
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 照旧加糖和奶精 对吧？- 对
- You still take cream and sugar right?
- Yeah.
我想现在说抱歉大概太晚了 对吗？
So suppose it's a little late for an apology, huh?
你说的很对
You suppose correctly.
听着 婊子...
Look, bitch...
我要知道你是否会在我宝贝女儿面前动手？
I need to know if you're going to start any more shit around my baby girl.
别紧张...
You can relax for now.
我可不会在孩子面前宰了你
I'm not going to murder you in front of your child, okay?
你比比尔更理性一点 我想你也不会那样做
That's being more irational than Bill led me to believe you were capable of.
我缺的是慈悲 同情 和宽恕...
It's mercy, compassion and forgiveness lack...
...而不是理性
...not irationality.
听着...
Look...
...我知道我害了你
...I know I fucked you over.
害得你很惨 我希望我没做 但是我做了
I fucked you over bad. I wish to God I hadn't, but I did.
你有权利来讨回公道
You have every right to want to get even.
不...不是...
No no, no, no, no.
讨回公道？啥叫公道？
No. To get even, even-steven...
我得宰了你...
I would have to kill you...
...再去宰了你女儿...
...go up to Nikkis room kill her...
然后等你丈夫 好心的贝尔医生回家 再宰了他...
...then wait for your husband, the good Dr. Bell, to come home and kill him.
这才叫公道 我们才会谁也不欠谁
That would be even Vernita That'd be about square.
听着 如果时光能倒流我一定不会做 但是这不可能
Look, if I could go back in a machine, I would. But I can't.
我现在只能说我已经重新做人了
All can tell you is that I'm a different person now.
哦 好极了 可我不在乎
Oh great. I don't care.
尽管如此 我知道我不配你的施舍与宽恕
Be that as it may, I know I don't deserve your mercy or your forgiveness.
但是为了过去的事和我女儿 我求你宽恕
However, I beseech you for both on behalf of my daughter.
婊子 别说了
Bitch, you can stop right there.
虽然我不想在你女儿面前宰了你...
Just because I have no wish to murder you in front of your daughter...
并不表示你拿她来做幌子 我就会同情你
...doesn't mean that parading her around in front of me will inspire sympathy.
咱们来有一桩买卖未了
You and I have unfinished business.
就算你这四年来 做尽了善事...
And not a goddamned thing you've done in the subsequent four years...
...无论如何都不能使我改变心意
. including getting knocked up is going to change that.
那咱们什么何时了结？
So when do we do this?
这个嘛 就看你想什么时候死？
It all depends. When do you want to die?
明天？后天？
Tomorrow? The day after tomorrow?
- 今晚如何 婊子？- 好极了！ 哪里？
- How about tonight, bitch?
- Splendid. Where?
离这儿一哩左右 有个我教孩子打棒球的球场
There's a baseball diamond where I coach Litte League about a mile from here.
我们半夜两点半见 全身穿黑色衣服...
We meet there around 2:30 in the morning dressed all in black.
头发绑黑丝袜
Your hair in a black stocking.
我们就比剑 然后就一了百了
And we have us a knife fight. We won't be bothered.
现在...
Now...
...我得给妮琪准备一些干b点心
...I have to fix Nikkis cerieal.
比尔总是说你是他见过最会用刀的女人之一
Bill always said you were one of the best ladies with an edged weapon.
去他妈的咧 他自己的剑术也不怎样
Fuck you bitch. I know he didn't qualify that shit.
你就准备去见阎王吧 黑曼巴
So you can just kiss my motherfucking ass, Black Mamba.
黑曼巴...
Black Mamba
我才配叫做黑曼巴
I should have been mother fucking Black Mamba.
至于用什么刀？你就用以前的那种屠刀也行
Weapon of choice? If you want to stick with your butcher knife, that's fine by me.
真好笑 婊子
Very funny, bitch.
真好笑！
Very funny.
我不是故意要在你面前下手
It was not my intention to do this in front of you.
所以我很抱歉
For that, lm sorry.
不过你可以相信我...
But you can take my word for it:
你妈其实已经知道 会有这样的下场
Your mother had it coming.
你长大以后...
When you grow up...
...如果还是放不下这仇...
...if you still feel raw about it...
...我会等着你
...l'll be waiting.
那些真正的战士...
For those regarded as warriors...
...在战斗之中...
... when engaged in combat...
...唯一的目的 就是要消灭敌人
... the vanquishing of thine enemy can be the warriors only concern.
压抑所有人性里的情绪和同情...
Suppress all human emotions and compassion...
...铲除所有的路上的阻碍 就算是上帝或佛祖都一样
... kill whoever stands in thy way, even if that be Lord God,
[复仇名单－五人]
[1 石井尾莲 代号棉口蛇 (完成)]
[2 芙妮塔・格林 代号铜头蛇]
or Buddha himself.
这就是战斗艺术中的真理
This truth lies at the heart of the art of combat...
[滦』醭]
[第二章 － 浴血新娘]
[四年半前 德州艾帕索市]
接着 我们得到了一些纪录
... and next, we got some record.
Very own wildman, Dharlie Feathers.
好了 向我详细汇报这血案的细节 儿子一号
We I give me the gory details, Son Number One.
简直是他妈的大屠杀 老爸
It's a goddamn massacre, Pop.
用执行死刑的方式 宰了所有婚礼上的人
They wiped out the whole wedding party, execution-style.
给我个人数
Give me a figure.
九个尸体
Nine dead bodies.
就是所有一箩筐的人:
And we're talking the whole shebang:
新娘 新郎...
Bride, groom...
...牧师 牧师的老婆...
...reverend, reverend's wife.
妈的 他们连弹风琴的老黑也宰了
Hell, they even shot that old colored fella that plays the organ.
似乎是某人背叛了什么帮派 然后却摆不平他们
Seems like someone objected to the union and wasn't able to hold their peace.
哇～ 圣母啊！
Good gravy, Marie.
我就跟你说了嘛 老爸
What'd I tell you, Pop?
看起来像个尼加拉瓜的大坟场
Looks like a goddamn Nicaraguan death squad.
竟然在敬拜上帝的净土上发生这种惨案
You better shit-can that blasphemy boy. You in a house of worship.
真令人难过 老爸
Sorry, Pop.
这是职业杀手干的
This is the work of professionals.
我猜是墨西哥黑帮干的
I'd guesstimate Mexican mafia hit squad.
四或五个人
Four, maybe five strong.
你怎么知道？
How can you tell?
杀人的手法多干净啊
Well a sure and steady hand did this.
绝不是业余的
This ain't no squirrelly amateur.
真是心狠手辣啊！
This is the work of a salty dog.
你可以从俐落的刀法看出来
You can tell by the cleanness of the carnage.
这场血腥的惨案 似乎是...
Now a kill-crazy rampage though it may be...
...精心策划过的
...all the colors are kept inside the line.
如果你是个蠢蛋 一定会拍手叫好的
If you was a moron, you could a most admire it.
新娘是谁？
Who's the bride?
不知道
Don't know.
结婚证书上是艾琳・麦克维利
The name on the marrage certificate is Arlene Machiavelli
是假名字
That's a fake.
因为她穿着婚纱 我们一直称她为新娘
We've al just been calling her "The Bride" on account of the dress.
看得出来 她怀孕了
You can tell she was pregnant.
凶手一定是条疯狗 才会朝这漂亮新娘的头上来一枪
He must be a mad dog to shoot a goddamn good-looking gal like that in the head.
看看她
Look at her.
亮丽的头发 大大的眼睛
Hay-colored hair, big eyes.
她简直是个浴血天使
She's a little blood-splattered angel.
－儿子一号  －在
- Son Number One?
- Yeah?
打电话给瑞根 妈的 这婆娘没死
This tall drink of cocksucker ain't dead.
[艾儿・德莱芙－毒蛇暗杀帮成员]
[代号: 加州山蛇]
我或许从没喜欢过你
Might never have liked you.
事实上 我讨厌你
Point in fact, I despise you.
但是这不表示 我不尊敬你
But that shouldn't suggest that I don't respect you.
能在梦中死去...
Dying in our sleep...
是很多人求之不得的享受
...is a luxury that our kind is rarely afforded.
我的礼物...送你的
My gift to you.
讨厌！
For fucks sake.
哈 比尔
Hello Bill.
她现况如何？
What's her condition?
昏迷中
Comatose.
她在哪儿？
Where is she?
我现在就站在她身旁
I'm standing over her right now.
好孩子
That's my girl
艾儿 你任务取消了
Elle, you will abort the mission.
啥？！
What?!
我们欠她 所以不该杀她
We owe her better than that.
才不 你啥狗屁也不欠她
Oh you don't owe her shit.
小声一点好不好？
Will you keep your voice down?
你啥狗屁也不欠她
You don't owe her shit!
我能说件事吧？
May I say one thing?
说吧
Speak.
你们都海扁了她一顿 但是没杀她
Y'all beat the hell out of that woman, but you didn't kill her.
我给了她脑门一枪 但是她心脏还是跳个不停
And I put a bullet in her head but her heart just kept on beating.
你那一只美丽的蓝眼也看到了
Now you saw that your self with your own beautiful blue eye.
不是吗？
Did you not?
我们已经对这位女士下了很多毒手...
We've done a lot of things to this lady.
如果她真的醒过来 咱们就再下毒手
And if she ever wakes up, we'll do a whole lot more.
但有件事咱们不能干...
But one thing we won't do...
...就是像鼠辈一样半夜偷溜进去...
...is sneak into her room in the night like a filthy rat...
...在睡梦中宰了她
... and kill her in her sleep.
我们不能干这种事的原因是...
And the reason we won't do that thing...
...因为这太下流了
...is because that thing would lower us.
你同意吗？
Don't you agree, Miss Driver?
我想是吧
I guess.
这你还要考虑？
Do you really have to guess?
不 其实不用再考虑
No. I don't really have to guess.
我知道
I know.
回家吧 甜心
Come on home, honey.
遵命
Affirmative.
我非常爱你
I love you very much.
我也爱你
I love you too.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
你一定他妈的认为很好笑 对吧？
Thought that was pretty fucking funny, didn't you?
给你个忠告 驴头:
Word of advice shithead:
别给我醒过来
Don't you ever wake up.
[四年后]
现在...这就是我...
This moment, this is me...
...最痛苦的时候
...at my most masochistic.
比尔 这是你的骨肉...
Bill, it's your baby...
我的孩子！
My baby.
四年了 四年了
Four years. Four years.
价钱是$75一次 哥儿们
Price is $75 a fuck, my friend.
- 怎样 你要不要上？- 喔 当然 伙计
- You getting your freak on, or what?
- Oh, yeah, boy.
20 40 60 75...好咧
20, 40, 60, 75. Yeah.
现在来讲规矩 第一 不可以打她
Now here's the rules. Rule number one: No punching her.
明天护士看到她鼻青脸肿或少颗牙什么的 就麻烦了
Nurse comes in tomorrow and she got a shiner orless teeth, jig's up.
无论如何都不能用拳头捶她
So no knuckle sandwiches under no circumstances.
还有 她那个小洞会出水 只是种反射动作
And by the way, this cunt's a spitter. It's a motor reflex thing.
不管有没出水 都不许打她
But spit or no, no punching.
第一条规矩听清楚了吧？
We absolutely clear on rule number one?
- 嗯  - 很好
- Yeah
- Good.
第二 不准咬 也不可吸出红印子
Now, rule number two: No monkey bites, no hickeys in fact.
就是不准留下任何痕迹 只要不犯规就行啦 兄弟
No leaving no marks of no kind. After that, it's all good, buddy.
你要干几次都行 反正她也不会拒绝
Her plumbing don't work no more so come in her all you want.
不要太大声 不要弄的一团糟 我20分钟后回来
Keep the noise down. Try not to make a mess. I'll be back in 20.
好咧
Yeah.
喔 对了 还有...
Oh! Shit. By the way,
有时候 她的禄嵯裆匙右谎干
sometimes this chick's cooch can get drier than a bucket of sand.
如果她很干 用这给她润滑一下 你就可以上了
If she dry, just lube up with this and you'll be good to go.
好好享用吧 老朋友
Bon apptit, good buddy.
哦 好耶
Oh, yeah
哇塞 你可是我今天干过最漂亮的啦
Oh, goddamn, you are the best-looking girl've had today.
喂 猛虎 时间到啦
Yo, stud! Time's up, buddy
不管你完事没 我要进来咯
I'm coming in ready or not.
哥们儿 玩的够爽吗？
Good buddy, did you have your self a good time man?
啊！
Whoa.
比尔在哪儿？
Where's Bill?
Where's Bill?!
- 求你别再打了  - 比尔在哪儿？
- Please stop hitting me
- Where's Bill?
- 我不知道比尔是谁！ - 放屁！
- I don't know who Bill is!
- Bullshit!
他们说 你是个可爱的小苹果
Well, ain't you the slice of cutie pie they said you was?
你是无名氏 没人知道你的事
Jane Doe. We don't know shit about you.
我从德州汉兹威尔市来 我叫巴克 我是来操你的
Well, I'm from Huntsville, Texas. My name's Buck and I'm here to fuck.
你叫巴克 对吧？
Your name's Buck. Right?
你来操我的 对吧？
And you came here to fuck. Right?
滦』醭
"Pussy Wagon"
妈的 烂人
You fucker.
德州 嗯
Texas. Okay.
动一动 脚姆趾
Wiggle your big toe.
当我坐在巴克的货车后面 试图让我四肢恢复知觉
As I lay in Buck's truck trying to will my limbs out of entropy...
动一动 脚姆趾
Wiggle your big toe.
我看到那些害我的人的脸
I saw the faces of the cunts who did this to me and the dick responsible.
所有致命毒蛇暗杀帮的成员
Members all of Bill's brainchild. The Deadly Viper Assassination Squad.
当幸运之神会眷顾如此残忍又丑陋的复仇时...
When fortune smiles on something as violent and ugly as revenge...
...似乎就证明了不仅上帝存在...
... it seems proof like no other that not only does God exist...
...而且你正在执行k的旨意
... you're doing his will
即使当我还摸不清敌人的底细时...
At a tie when I knew the least about my enemies...
第一个出现在我复仇名单上的是石井尾莲
... the first name on my death list, O-Ren Ishii...
...最容易找到的
... was the easiest to find.
因为当一个人好不容易当上了日本黑道女王时...
But when one manages the hard task of becoming queen of Tokyo's underworld.
...一定会大肆张扬 对吧？
... one doesn't keep it a secret, does one?
[石井尾莲 － 致命毒蛇暗杀帮的成员]
[代号：棉口蛇]
[第三章 － 石井尾莲的崛起]
石井尾莲出生于东京一个美军基地
O- Ren Ishii was born on an American military base in Tokyo, Japan.
这个中日混血的魔女...
The half-Japanese half Chinese-American army brat...
在九岁时第一次认识到死亡
... made her first acquaintance with death at the age of 9.
就在那时她亲眼见到父母...
It was at that age she witnessed the death of her parents...
死在残酷的黑帮大佬松本之手
... at the hands of Japan's most ruthless yakuza boss.
黑帮大佬松本
Boss Matsumoto.
妈咪！
Mommy.
她发誓要复仇
She swore revenge.
幸运的是 松本是个恋童癖
Luckily for her, Boss Matsumoto was a pedophile.
11岁那年 她终于报了仇
At 11, she got her revenge.
看看我 松本
Look at me Matsumoto...
看看我的脸
... take a good look at my face.
看看我的眼睛
Look at my eyes.
看看我的脸鼻子
Look at my nose.
看看我的下巴
Look at my chin.
看看我的嘴
Look at my mouth.
似曾相识吗？
Do I look familiar?
是不是很像某个被你谋杀的人...
Do I look like somebody you murdered.
20岁之前 她已成为世界顶尖的女杀手之一
By 20, she was one of the top female assassins in the world.
25岁时她参与了一次行动 谋杀了9个无辜之人...
At 25 she did her part in the killing of nine innocent people...
包括我未出世的女儿
... including my unborn daughter...
在一个德州艾帕索市的小结婚教堂
... in a small wedding chapel in El Paso, Texas.
但就在四年前的那天...
But on that day four years ago...
她犯了一个大错...
... she made one big mistake.
当时她应该杀掉10个人
She should have killed ten.
然而 在我如愿以偿之前...
However, before satisfaction would be mine...
先要做的是...
... first things first.
动一动 脚拇趾
Wiggle your big toe.
最难的一关过了
Hard part's over.
现在 其他娃娃脚趾也动一动
Now, let's get these other piggies wiggling.
[13小时之后]
欢迎来艾欧航空 需要帮忙吗？
Welcome to Air O. May I help you?
冲绳...单程
Okinawa One-way
[冲绳]
[第四章 － 冲绳男子]
[日本冲绳岛]
嗨
Hi.
欢迎...
Welcome...
欢迎
Welcome.
你是英国人？
You English?
几乎对了...是美国
Almost American.
美国人 欢迎 欢迎
American Welcome, welcome.
多莫 (日语:你好)
我的英语...很好哦
My English very good.
你刚说"多莫"！
You said domo.
你会说日文吗？
Can you speak Japanese?
哦 不是啦 只是从昨天开始学的几个字
No no. Just a few words I learned since yesterday.
- 嗯...我能坐寿司吧吗？- 当然 请坐
- May I sit at the bar?
- Oh, sure Sure sure. Please, sit.
你还学了其他什么字？
What other words did you learn?
哦 请等一下
Just a minute.
有客人 快上茶
We have a customer. Bring out some tea, quickly.
我在看连续剧
I'm watching my soap operas.
妈的
Oh, shit.
懒鬼
Lazy bastard...
去你妈的连续剧 快啦
Screw your soap opera... hurry up.
茶很烫 干脆你自己上一次茶吧
The teas hot Why don't you serve it yourself for once?
闭嘴 快给我滚出来
Shut up! Get your ass out here!
请原谅我
Excuse me.
你还会说其他什么日语？
What other Japanese do you know?
哦...我想想...阿里嘎多(谢谢)
Oh, let's see.
阿里嘎多...嗯
Good.
我刚说过多莫 对吧？
I already said domo, right?
对 对 对
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
抠尼几哇
不对 抠尼奇哇(你好)
抠-尼-奇-哇 请跟我说
Please repeat.
抠尼奇哇
啊 很好 很好
Perfect. Good, good, good.
你说的就像日本人说的一样好
You say Japanese word like you're Japanese.
- 你在嘲笑我吧 - 不 很正经的说
- Now you're making fun of me.
- No. Serious business.
发音很棒
Pronunciation very good.
你说阿里嘎多
就像我们说阿里嘎多一样
You say ariga to. Like we say ariga to.
谢谢你...我是说 阿里嘎多
Well, thank you. I mean, ariga to.
你应该学日语 很简单的
You should learn Japanese. Very easy.
- 真的？我听说好像很难 - 是很难
- No kidding? I heard it was kind of hard.
- Most difficult.
但是你很有天赋
But, you have Japanese tongue.
喔 老天
Oh my God.
喂～怎么还没上茶？
快点 妈的
Hey, what the hell happened to the tea. Hurry up... goddamit.
又懒又蠢
Lazy oaf...
你要啥？
What'd ya want?
什么？
Beg your pardon?
喝什么？
Drink.
哦 对了 一壶温清酒
Oh yes, a bottle of warm sake, please.
温清酒？好的很
Warm sake? Very good.
一壶温清酒
One warm sake!
清酒？大白天喝酒？
Sake? In the middle of the day?
白天 晚上 日正午
谁在乎 去拿清酒
- Day, night afternoon Who gives a damn. Get the sake.
为什么每次都是我去拿！
How come I always have to get the sake?
你给我听好
You listen well...
三十年来都是你切鱼 我拿酒
For thirty years you make the fish. I get the sake.
如果这里是皇军
我已经成了将军(清酒品牌)
If this were the military, I'd be General by now.
哦 你成了将军...
Oh, so youd be General huh?
如果你是将军
那我就是天皇啦
If you were General, I'd be Emperor,
结果还是你去拿酒
所以给我闭嘴 快去拿酒
and you'd stlll get the sake. So shut up and get the sake!
你听懂没？
Do you understand?
我不是天生光头 是剃光的
你听懂没？
I'm not bald, okay? I shaved my head. Do you under stand?
对不起
Sorry.
哦 第一次来日本？
First time in Japan?
是什么风把你吹来的？
What brings you to Okinawa?
我是来找一个人
Came to see a man.
哦 是吗？
Oh, yeah?
你有朋友住冲绳？
You have a friend live in Okinawa?
不是
Not quite.
不是朋友？
Not friend?
- 我们没见过面  - 没见过！？
- I never met him.
- Never?
是谁啊...我能冒昧的问吗？
Who is he may I ask?
服部半藏
Hattori Hanzo.
你找服部半藏干嘛？
What do you want with Hattori Hanzo?
我需要一把日本刀
I need Japanese steel.
为什么要日本刀
Why do you need Japanese steel?
我要杀一只黄鼠狼
I have vermin to kill.
那一定是大老鼠 你才需要服部半藏武士刀
You must have big rats you need Hattori Hanzo's steel.
非常大
Huge.
我可以吗？
May?
可以
You may.
等等
Wait.
试试上面第二把
Try the second one down.
奇怪...
Funny...
你喜欢武士刀
...you like samurai swords.
我喜欢棒球
I like baseball.
我只是想要让你看看
I wanted to show you these.
但是 像你见识这么广的人 也一定知道...
However someone as you, who knows so much, must surely know...
我已经不再造杀人的武器了
... I no longer make instruments of death.
这里的一切 我留着只是为了艺术价值和过去的回忆
What I have here I keep for their aesthetic and sentimental value.
话说回来 我当然很骄傲我一生的心血
Yet proud as I am of my life 's work...
不过我已经退休了
... I have retired.
那么就给我一把吧
Then give me one of these.
这些是非卖品
These are not for sale.
我没说"卖" 我是说"给"
I didn't say "sell me" I said "give me".
为什么...我要帮助你？
Why should I help you?
因为我的那只黄鼠狼 是你以前的徒弟
Because my vermin is a former student of yours.
就因为他是你学生
And considering the student...
所以我说你有很大的责任
I'd say you have a rather large obligation.
[比尔]
你可以睡这儿
You can sleep here.
我需要一个月...来铸这把刀
It will take me a month to make the sword.
我建议你用这段时间来练习
I suggest you spend it practicing
我已经做了一件...
I've completed doing...
28年前我向神起誓...
...what I swore an oath to God, 28 years ago,
我绝不再做的事
...to never do again.
我造了一个能杀人的东西
I have created "something that kills peope."
就这一点来说 我是成功了
And in that purpose, was a success.
我之所以做了 因为内心深处...我同情你的遭遇
I've done this because philosophically,
I am sympathetic to your aim.
不是我吹牛 这是我铸过最好的一把刀
I can tell you with no ego, this is my finest sword.
万一你的复仇之路 遇上了神...
If on your journey, you should encounter God...
神也会被切两半
...God will be cut.
黄发武士...
Yellow-haired warrior...
去吧
Go.
谢谢
Domo.
[第五章 － 蓝叶茶室对决]
德州艾帕索市惨案的一年后
It was one year after
the massacre in El Paso, Texas,
比尔给他的日本支系经济与精神上的援助...
that Bill backed his Nippon progeny
financially and philosophically in her.
帮助她与其他黑帮几乎是戏剧化的争夺...
Shakespearean-in-magnitude
power struggle with the other yakuza clans.
整个东京黑社会的统治权
over who would rule vice
in the city of Tokyo.
当硝烟散尽后...
When the final sword
was sheathed,
是石井尾莲和她强力的武装团...
It was O-Ren Ishii
and her powerful posse...
"疯狂88人组" 取得了胜利
...the Crazy 88,
that proved the victor.
尾莲右边那个美妇人
The pretty lady to O-Ren's right
穿得像"星际旅行"里反派角色的那个...
who's dressed like she's a villain on "Star Trek"
是尾莲的律师 好友和少尉...
is O-Ren's lawyer, best friend,
and second lieutenant.
法美混血儿，苏菲・法塔尔
The half-French,
half-Japanese Sofie Fatale.
比尔的另一位得意门生...
Another former protegee
of Bill's.
那个穿学生制服的年轻女孩
The young girl in the school-girl uniform
是尾莲的私人保镖 17岁的夕张"勾勾"
is O-Ren's personal bodyguard,
17-year-old Gogo Yubari.
勾勾也许还年轻 但她年龄上所欠缺的
Gogo may be young, but what she lacks in age
她用疯狂来弥补
she makes up for in madness.
你喜欢法拉利吗？
Do you like Ferraris?
法拉利？义大利垃圾
Ferrari... italian trash.
你想干我吗？
Do you want to screw me?
别笑，你想干我吗？想还是不想？
Don't laugh! Do you want to screw me, yes or no?
想
Yes.
现在如何 大男孩？
How 'bout now, big boy?
你还想插入我么？
Do you still wish to penetrate me...
还是我...
...or is it I...
还是我已经插入你了？
...or is it I... who has penetrated you?
明白我的意思了吧？
See what I mean?
那个身着黑西装，戴着加藤面具的秃子是莫庄尼
The bald guy in the black suit
and the Kato mask is Johnny Mo,
他是尾莲私人军队"疯狂88人组"的上将军
the head general of O-Ren's
personal army, the Crazy 88.
如果你在疑惑...
And just in case
you were wondering
为什么一个中日混血的美国人...
how could a half-breed
Japanese-Chinese American
能成为日本东京黑帮老大中的老大？
become the boss of all bosses
in Tokyo, Japan,
让我告诉你...
I'll tell you.
关于尾莲的血统和国籍...
The subject of O-Ren's blood
and nationality
只有一次成为议会的议题
came up before the council
only once.
那是在尾莲接管这罪恶的黑帮议会的当天晚上
The night O-Ren assumed power
over the crime council.
那个一心一意想要破坏会议气氛的大佬田中
The man who seems bound and determined
to break the mood is Boss Tanaka.
田中在想的是...
And what Boss Tanaka
thinks is...
田中老大！
Boss Tanaka!
你这疯狂的举动是什么意思？
What's the meaning of this outburst?
现在是庆祝的时候！
This is a time for celebration!
我们到底在庆祝什么？
And what exactly are we celebrating?
我们光荣议会的堕落吗？
The perversion of our illustrious council?
田中！ 你疯了吗？
Tanaka, have you gone mad?
我不会容忍这个的！
I will not tolerate this!
你对我们的大姐无理 道歉！
You're disrespecting our sister! Apologize!
田中君 你说的堕落是指什么？
Tanaka-San, of what perversion do you speak?
我的父亲...
My father...
...我和你们的父亲...
...along with yours,
和你们的父亲创建了这个议会
and along with yours, started this council.
当你们...
And while...
像笨驴般傻笑时...
...you laugh like stupid donkeys...
...他们却在阴间哭泣...
...they weep in the afterlife...
闭嘴！
- Shut up!
...伤心今天议会的堕落！
...over the perversion committed today!
荒谬！
Outrageous!
田中 侮辱了这个议会的是你
Tanaka, it is you who insults this council!
混蛋！
Bastard!
你妈的！
Fuck face!
各位...
Gentlemen.
田中似乎心里有话要说
Tanaka obviously has something on his mind.
无论如何 请先让他说出来
By all means, allow him to express it.
我要说的是关于这议会的堕落
Speak, of the perversion done to this
council,
我爱它...
...which I love...
更胜我自己的孩子
...more than my own chidren,
是因为让一个中日混血的美国婊子成为首脑
...by making a Chinese Jap-American
half breed bitch its leader!
为了让你们明白我是多么严肃，
So that you understand how serious I am...
下面我要用英语说
...I'm going to say this in English.
作为你们的首领...
- As your leader...
我时常用尊敬的态度鼓励你们 提出对我领导方式的质疑
I encourage you from time to time,
and always in a respectful manner, to question my logic.
对于我认为是最明智的决定 你们如果不信服的话 请告诉我
If you're unconvinced a particular plan of action I've decided is the wisest, tell me so.
也请给我机会来说服你们
But allow me to convince you.
我现在在这里向你们保证 没有不可以谈的议题...
And promise you, right here and now, no subject will ever be taboo.
除了现在正在讨论的议题之外
Except, of course, the subject
that was just under discussion.
你要付出的代价是...
The price you pay
对于我的中美血统有任何负面的评价 我就会取你的首级
for bringing up either my Chinese or American heritage
as a negative is, I collect your fucking head.
就像这个混蛋一样
Just like this fucker here.
如果你们这群龟儿子还有什么话要说 现在正是时候！
Now, if any of you sons of bitches
got anything else to say, now is the fucking time!
我想也是
Didn't think so.
各位 现在散会
Gentlemen, this meeting is adjourned.
去东京一张单程机票
One ticket to Tokyo pease.
勾勾
Gogo.
对于他们任何无理的要求 你都要说 "是 是 是"
You have to say "Yes, yes, yes" to
any selfish demands they make.
他们的要求真的很荒谬
They demand ridiculous things.
闭嘴！ 你知道如果他们听到了 你会怎么样吗？
Shut up... Do you know what would
happen if they heard you?
会发生什么？
What's gonna happen?
你没听说田中帮吗？
Did you hear about the Tanaka clan?
你的头会被砍掉
You're gonna get your head chopped off.
我可不希望那样
对，是我
Yes, it's me.
如果你给我们一个联系号码，我们会回覆的
And if you give us a contact number,
we will get back to you.
喂 你！
你知道你让我想起谁吗？
Who do you remind me of?
查理布朗！
Charlie Brown!
对啊 他确实长得像查理布朗
You're right, he does look like
Charlie Brown.
查理布朗
4个香肠匹萨
Four pepperoni pizzas.
我们菜单上没有...
That's not on our menu...
我不管 去拿来 妈的！
I don't care, bring them, goddammit!
喂...喂...查理，给我一个吻
Hey... hey... Charlie, give me a kiss.
石井尾莲！
O-Ren Ishii!
你和我还有些恩怨未了！
You and I have unfinished business!
查理不朗 滚
Charlie Brown, beat it.
米奇
Miki.
把这婊子给剁了！
TEAR THE BITCH APART!
我说 尾莲 你还有属下来送死吗？
So, O-Ren, anymore subordinates
for me to kill?
嗨
Hi!
勾勾 对吧？
Gogo, right?
答对啦
Bingo.
你是黑曼巴？
And you're Black Mamba.
我们的名声响亮
Our reputations precede us.
对吧？
Don't they?
勾勾 我知道你必须保护女主人
Gogo, I know you feel you must
protect your mistress.
但是我乞求你...
But I beg you.
快让开
Walk away.
你这叫乞求？
You call that begging?
你应该哀求才对
You can beg better than that.
你和我想的一样吗？
Is that what I think it is?
你不会认为有那么简单 对吧？
You didn't think it was
gonna be that easy, did you?
你知道 我当时的确是这么认为
You know, for a second there,
yeah, I kind of did.
傻孩子
Silly rabbit.
孩子才会这样想
Trix are for...
孩子们
Kids.
这就是你混黑道的下场！
This is what you get
for fucking around with yakuzas!
滚回家找你妈妈去吧！
Go home to your mother!
你们这些侥幸还活着的 快逃命去吧
Those of you lucky enough to still
have your lives take them with you!
但是...
However...
留下你们的断肢
...leave the limbs you've lost.
他们现在是我的了
They belong to me now.
除了你 苏菲！
Except you, Sofie!
你待在原地别动
You stay right where you are.
你的兵器令人印象深刻
Your instrument
is quite impressive.
哪里造的？
Where was it made?
冲绳
Okinawa.
是冲绳什么人打造的？
Whom in Okinawa made you this steel?
这是服部半藏的
This is Hattori Hanzo steel.
你说谎！
YOU LIE!
虽然刀剑不会累
Swords however, never get tired.
我希望你还留有足够的精力
Hope you've saved your energy.
如果没有...
If you haven't...
你撑不了五分钟的
...you might not last five minutes.
从刚才的情况来看...
But as last looks go,
你会更惨
you could do worse.
你这傻傻的白人女孩 却偏偏爱玩日本武士刀
Silly Caucasian girl likes
to play with samurai swords.
你虽然不能像武士般打斗...
You may not be able to fight
like a samurai.
但是你却可以死得像个武士
But you can at least die
like a samurai.
放马过来...
Attack me...
...尽你所能
...with everything you have.
我刚才看轻你了...
For ridiculing you earlier...
我道歉
...I apologize.
我接受
Accepted.
准备好了？
Ready?
来吧
Come on.
那真的是一把服部半藏的刀
That really was a Hattori Hanzo sword.
苏菲
Sofie.
我的苏菲
My Sofie.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
请，请宽恕我的背叛
Please.
Please forgive my betrayal.
不要再提了
No more of that.
但是...
But still...
没什么可但是的...
But still nothing.
除了我为了她对我聪慧的苏菲做的一切而感到心痛之外
Except my aching heart over what she's done
to my beautiful and brilliant Sofie.
我让你活着有两个原因
I've kept you alive
for two reasons.
第一 要问你话
The first reason is information.
去死吧 你这愚蠢的金发女人 我什么也不会说
Burn in Hell, you stupid, stupid blonde! I'll tell you nothing.
但是我还是要问你
But I am gonna ask you
questions.
每次你不回答的话...
And every time
you don't give me answers,
我就从你身上割点什么下来
I'm gonna cut something off.
我保证 一定是你最怕失去的部分
And I promise you, they will be things you will miss!
给我你的另一只手！
- Give me your other arm!
我要所有有关致命毒蛇成员们的信息
I want all the information
on the Deadly Vipers.
如果让你猜...
If you had to guess...
他们在干嘛...
What they've been doing.
她为什么要留你活口
Why she left you alive...
在哪里可以找到他们
And where I can find them.
你的猜测是什么？
What would be your guess?
我不需要猜
Guessing won't be necessary.
她已经告诉我了
She informed me.
她说我可以因为二个原因而保留我邪恶的生命
She said I could keep
my wicked life for two reasons.
像我以前说的...
As I said before,
我因为二个原因而让你继续你邪恶的生命
I've allowed you to keep your
wicked life for two reasons.
第二个原因 是你可以亲口告诉他
And the second reason is
so you can tell him, in person
今晚这里发生什么事...
everything that happened
here tonight.
我要他亲眼见证我的慈悲...
I want him to witness
the extent of my mercy
从你残破的身躯上看到
by witnessing
your deformed body.
我要你告诉他所有你告诉我的讯息
I want you to tell him all the
information you just told me.
我要他知道我所知道的
I want him to know what I know.
我要他知道我想要他知道的
I want him to know
I want him to know.
我要他们全部都知道...
And I want them all to know
他们将会像尾莲一样死去
they'll all soon be
as dead as O-Ren.
复仇不是一条直路
Revenge is never a straight line.
而是一片森林
It's a forest.
就像在森林里容易迷路...
And like a forest it's easy to lose your way...
迷失了方向也忘了从哪里进来的
...to get lost... to forget where you came in.
那个女人有报仇的权力
That woman deserves her revenge.
还有 我们都该死
And we deserve to die.
她应该受折磨直到咽下最后一口气
She must suffer
to her last breath.
你是怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
别忘了我是什么人
I'm the man.
还有一件事，苏菲
One more thing, Sofie.
她知不知道她女儿还活着？
Is she aware her daughter
is still aive?